<resources>
    <string name="app_name">YuvAgri</string>
    <string name="sign_up">Sign Up</string>
    <string name="yuvagri">YuvAgri</string>
    <string name="crop_guidance_app">Crop Guidance App</string>
    <string name="login">Login</string>
    <string name="welcome_to">Welcome To</string>
    <string name="login_here">Login Here</string>
    <string name="email_phone_no">Email/Phone No.</string>
    <string name="password">Password</string>
    <string name="new_user">New User?</string>
    <string name="sign_up1">Sign Up</string>
    <string name="title_activity_soil">SoilActivity</string>
    <string name="prompt_email">Email</string>
    <string name="prompt_password">Password</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in">Sign in or register</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in_short">Sign in</string>
    <string name="welcome">"Welcome !"</string>
    <string name="invalid_username">Not a valid username</string>
    <string name="invalid_password">Password must be >5 characters</string>
    <string name="login_failed">"Login failed"</string>
    <string name="full_name">Full Name</string>
    <string name="already_signed_up">Already Signed Up?</string>
    <string name="sign_up_here">Sign Up Here</string>
    <string name="red_soil">Red Soil</string>
    <string name="loamy_soil">Loamy Soil</string>
    <string name="sandy_soil">Sandy Soil</string>
    <string name="username">Username</string>
    <string name="re_password">Re-Password</string>
    <string name="clay_soil">Clay soil</string>
    <string name="black_soil">Black Soil</string>

    <string name="paddy1">Paddy farmers used to get their fields ready before the rainy season. The weeds are cleared and the field is ploughed by buffaloes or tractors to a depth of few inches. Manures and fertilizers are added to the soil. The whole surface then remained covered with water of about 2.5 cm. The field is then ready for receiving seedlings from the nursery.</string>
    <string name="paddy1h">Preparation of Field:</string>
    <string name="paddy2">Generally paddy seedlings are first prepared in nursery and then transplanting is done in the field after about 40 days. Although in some areas of India and Sri Lanka seeds have been sown directly in the field and the seedlings sprout when the rain comes. But yield of paddy from transplanting is greater than the direct sowing. The transplanted paddy also grows faster because of regular spacing and matures within a shorter period.</string>
    <string name="paddy2h">Transplantation:</string>
    <string name="paddy3">Paddy fields also require regular maintenance, such as occasional weeding and thinning out the more crowded patches, level of water is to be maintained according to the growth and the fields are drained dry before the crop is harvested.</string>
    <string name="paddy3h">Field Maintenance:</string>
    <string name="paddy4">The traditional harvesting system is either through a curved knife or a sharp-edged knife. It is very labour-intensive. Harvesting is done in the dry season, when the weather is sunny. Mechanical combines which cut and thresh are used in Japan.</string>
    <string name="paddy4h">Harvesting:</string>
    <string name="paddy5">After the paddy stalks have been gathered and dried for a brief spell, their threshing is usually done. By beating the sheaves against the bars, the grains are separated from the stalks. Now threshing machines have also been developed.</string>
    <string name="paddy5h">Threshing, Winnowing and Milling:</string>

    <string name="winnowing_is_a_process_of_removing_the_unwanted_particles_from_the_paddy_grains_the_simplest_way_is_by_pouring_the_paddy_down_from_a_height_on_a_windy_day_to_a_large_square_mat_on_open_ground_the_grains_fall_to_the_mat_while_lighter_chaff_blows_out_sometimes_hand_winnowing_machines_are_also_used">Winnowing is a process of removing the unwanted particles from the paddy grains. The simplest way is by pouring the paddy down from a height on a windy day to a large square mat on open ground. The grains fall to the mat while lighter chaff blows out. Sometimes hand-winnowing machines are also used.</string>
    <string name="milling_means_removal_of_the_yellowish_husks_from_paddy_so_that_white_or_polished_rice_is_obtained_in_a_rice_mill_the_paddy_is_made_to_pass_between_varying_sets_of_huller_or_rollers_till_it_is_milled_or_polished">Milling means removal of the yellowish husks from paddy so that white or polished rice is obtained. In a rice mill the paddy is made to pass between varying sets of huller or rollers till it is milled or polished.</string>
    <string name="although_there_are_several_varieties_of_rice_but_on_the_basis_of_their_location_two_varieties_have_been_identified_these_are_i_upland_rice_which_is_grown_on_upland_areas_and_ii_lowland_rice_which_grows_in_low_lying_and_marshy_areas"><![CDATA[Although, there are several varieties of rice, but on the basis of their location two varieties have been identified. These are: (i) upland rice, which is grown on upland areas; and (ii) lowland rice, which grows in low lying and marshy areas.]]></string>

    <string name="cotton">COTTON CROP</string>

    <string name="nursery">The seeds are generally sown in a seed bed and 4-6 week old seedlings are transplanting to the field. Cabbage seeds are sown on nursery beds to raise seedlings for transplanting in the field. Raised beds of size 3 x 0.6 m and 10-15 cm in height are prepared. About 70cm distance is kept between two beds to carry out intercultural operations such as watering, weeding, etc. The surface of beds should be 2 smooth and well levelled. Well-decomposed FYM @ 2-3 kg/m is added at the time of bed preparation. Raised beds are necessary to avoid problem of water logging in heavy soils. To avoid mortality of seedlings due to damping off, drenching of the beds with Bavistin (15-20g/10 litres of water) is effective.</string>

    <string name="sugarcane">Sugarcane Crop</string>
    <string name="groundnut">GROUNDNUT</string>
    <string name="jowar">JOWAR</string>
    <string name="potato">POTATO</string>
    <string name="greengram">GREEN GRAM</string>
    <string name="paddy">paddy</string>
    <string name="wheat">WHEAT CROP</string>
    <string name="cabbage">CABBAGE</string>
    <string name="email">Email</string>
    <string name="forgot_password">Forgot Password?</string>
    <string name="paddy_crops">Paddy</string>

    <string name="harvest">Cabbage is ready for harvest at 90-120 days after planting. Cabbage should be harvested promptly when the heads are firm and mature. Delaying harvest, even a few days beyond maturity can result in split heads and increased incidence of field disease.Harvesting immature heads, however, reduces yield, and the heads are too soft to resist handling damage. Immature heads also have a shorter shelf life than mature heads.\nThe head is harvested by bending it to one side and cutting it with a knife. The stalk should be cut flat and as close to the head as possible, yet long enough to retain two to four wrapper leaves. Extra leaves act as cushions during handling and may be desired in certain markets. The head should not be removed by snapping or twisting it since this practice damages the head and results in inconsistent stalk length. Broken stalks are also more susceptible to decay. As the heads are not ready for harvest at the same time, therefore they are harvested in stages based on the maturity of the heads.Harvested produce should always be stored in shade before packing.Yield of the cabbage varies greatly depending upon variety, maturity group and season of cultivation.Average yield obtained from early varieties is 25-30 t/ha and that of late type is 40-60 t/ha</string>
    <string name="manures">The fertilizer dose depends upon the fertility of soil and amount of organic manure applied to the crop. For a good yield, 15-20 tonnes of well-decomposed FYM is incorporated into the soil about 4 weeks before transplanting. Generally, application of 80-120 kg N, 60-100kg P2O5 and 60-120 kg K2O is recommended for optimum yield. Half the dose of N and entire amount of P and K is given at the time of transplanting. The balance N is given six weeks after transplanting or at the time of earthing up.</string>
    <string name="landpreparation">The field is ploughed to fine tilth by giving four to five ploughing with a sufficient interval between two ploughing. Planking should be done for proper levelling. The transplanting is done on the flat land, ridges or in furrows depending on climate and soil conditions. For early planting, ridge method is suitable especially in areas where the rains occur at the time of planting. In saline soils, planting in furrows and in dry areas transplanting on flat beds is recommended.The planting distance may vary according to variety, planting season and soil conditions. The following distances are generally recommended on the basis of maturity of varieties:\nEarly maturity varieties : 45 x 45 or 60 x 30 cm\nMid : 60 x 45 cm\nLate : 60 x 60 cm or 75 x 60 cm\nMethod of Planting:\nTransplanting should be done preferably in the morning or late evening. Before transplanting, the roots of the seedlings are dipped in a solution of Bavistin (2g/litre of water). Irrigation should be given immediately after transplanting. In some parts of the country, beds are first irrigated and then the seedlings are transplanted.</string>
    <string name="raising">About 300-500g of seed are sufficient for raising nursery required to plant one hectare. Prior to sowing seeds are treated with fungal culture of Trichoderma viride (4 g/ kg of seed) or Thiram (3g/ kg of seed) to avoid damage from damping-off disease. Sowing should be done thinly in lines spaced at 5-7 cm distance. Seeds are sown at a depth of 1-2 cm and covered with a fine layer of soil followed by light watering by water can. The beds should then be covered with dry straw or grass or sugarcane leaves to maintain required temperature and moisture. The watering should be done by water can as per the need till germination is completed. The cover of dry straw or grass is removed immediately after emergence of seed sprout. If there is over crowding of seedling due to thick sowing, the extra seedlings should be thinned out.The seedlings should be transplanted within 4-6 weeks of sowing. Older seedlings when transplanted result in poor growth and yield.</string>

    <string name="sugarcane1">Sugarcane Breeding Institute, Coimbatore, India, established in 1912, is mainly focusing on evolving superior varieties of sugarcane suitable for various agro climatic zones in India.The location is well suited for sugarcane breeding as the climate favours natural flowering of sugarcane and good seed set.Three regional centres of SBI located at Karnal (Haryana), Kannur and Agali (Kerala) assist the main centre in research trials and establishing nurseries.An user friendly website namely CaneInfo has been developed and launched to host detailed information on production technologies related to sugarcane across India.</string>
    <string name="sugarcane2">The normal practice in many parts of the world is to use commercial crop of sugarcane for seed purposes. Characteristics for good seed are seldom taken into consideration. Many growers do not care for seed quality and many of those who do, select the seed only at the sett cutting and planting stage. This is not enough. If a grower wants to be sure of getting good and disease free seed cane he should raise the seed crop separately. This crop should be kept completely free from pests and diseases by constant field scouting from the very beginning.Moreover, seed quality is not merely a matter of pest and disease freedom. Seed has to be in high water content and of good nutritional status. Neglect in raising good seed crop is one of the major defects in sugarcane cultivation all over the world.</string>
    <string name="sugarcane2h">Raising of Seed Cane Crop:</string>
    <string name="sugarcane3">Use of sugarcane seed from the commercial crop has been responsible for rapid multiplication of a large number of diseases like red rot, wilt, smut, ratoon stunting and grassy shoot which adversely affect the cane yield and quality. It is, therefore, raising of healthy and vigorous sugarcane crops for seed purpose is essential and recommended.Crop is ready in 7 - 8 months. Setts obtained from such crop contain healthy and sound buds, higher moisture content, adequate nutrients, higher amounts of reducing sugars, therefore, establish quickly and grow vigorously thus ensuring a good commercial main field crop</string>
    <string name="sugarcane4">Harvest the seed crop one day before planting to obtain higher percentage and uniform germination.\nPrepare the setts always one day before planting by giving sett treatment.\nPlanting material or seed cane should be free from aerial roots and splits.\nAvoid damage to buds while cutting setts.\nChange the seed material after every two to three seasons. In case if it is inevitable to use mature cane as seed, the top one-third portion can be used satisfactorily.</string>
    <string name="sugarcane4h">Preparation of Setts for Main Field Planting:</string>
    <string name="sugarcane5">Always use seed cane obtained from a seed crop of 7-8 months\nFree from disease and pest infestation like red rot, wilt, smut, ratoon stunting disease etc\nPossesses healthy buds without any damage in handling and transport.\nBuds with higher moisture content, adequate nutrients, higher amount of reducing sugars and viability.\nFree from aerial roots and splits.\nPure in quality</string>
    <string name="sugarcane5h">Deal Seed Cane:</string>

    <string name="wheat1">Wheat (Triticum spp.) occupies the prime position among the food crops in the world. In India, it is the second important food crop being next to rice and contributes to the total foodgrain production of the country to the extent of about 25%. Wheat has played a very vital role in stabilizing the foodgrain production in the country over the past few years.The origin of the durum wheats was probably in the region of Abyssinia, whereas the whole group of soft wheat, which includes the bread wheats, probably originated in the region of Pakistan, SouthWestern and the Southern parts of mountainous Bokhara.</string>
    <string name="wheat2">The ideal temperature requirement varies from plant type and stages of growth. The dwarf varieties require the following temperature for their growth and development:\nGrowth stages	Temperature requirement\nGermination	20 to 25 0 C mean daily temperature\nTillering	16 to 20 0 C mean daily temperature\nAccelerated growth	20 to 23 0 C mean daily temperature\nProper grain filling	23 to 25 0 C mean daily temperature.\nWheat plants are sensitive to very cold or frost injury at any stage of growth particularly at reproductive growth if temperature is below 150</string>
    <string name="wheat2h">Climate and Soil:</string>
    <string name="wheat3">The wheat crop requires a well-pulverized but compact seed bed for good and uniform germination. Three or four ploughings in the summer, repeated harrowing in the rainy season, followed by three or four cultivations and planking immediately before sowing produce a good, firm seed bed for the dry crop on alluvial soils. For the irrigated crop, the land is given a pre-sowing irrigation (palewa or raund) and the number of ploughings is reduced. Where white ants or other pests are a problem, Aldrin 5% or BHC 10% dust at the rate of 25 kg/ha should be applied to the soil after the last ploughing or before planking.</string>
    <string name="wheat3h">Land Preparation:</string>
    <string name="wheat4">a) Sowing time:\nBased on above temperature requirement it has been found that for indigenous wheat last week of October, for long duration dwarf varieties like Kalyansona, Arjun, etc. first fortnight of November and for short duration dwarf wheats like Sonalika, Raj 821 etc. second fortnight is the best sowing time. Under exceptionally late sown condition it may be delayed to latest by 1st week of December beyond which if area is very small transplanting may be practiced.\nb) Seed rate:\nGenerally, a seed rate of 100 kg/ha has been found to be sufficient for most of the varieties like Kalyan Sona, Arjun, Janak, etc.which have moderate tillering and medium sized grains. But a higher seed rate of 125 kg/ha is desirable for late sown wheat and normal sown for varieties like Sonalika, Raj 821 etc. which have bold grains and shy tillering habits.\nc) Spacing: :\nFor irrigated, timely sown wheat, a row spacing of 15 to 22.5 cm is followed, but 22.5 cm between the rows is considered to be the optimum spacing. Under irrigated late-sown conditions, a row spacing of 15-18 cm is the optimum. For dwarf wheats, the planting depth should be between 5 and 6 cm. Planting beyond this depth results in a poor stand. In the case of conventional tall varieties, the depth of sowing may be 8 or 9 cm.\nd) Seed treatment:\nThe seed of loose smut-susceptible varieties should be given solar or hot-water treatment. If the wheat seed is used only for sowing, and not for human consumption or for feeding cattle, it can be treated with Vitavax.</string>
    <string name="wheat4h">Sowing:</string>
    <string name="wheat5">It is desirable that 2 to 3 tonnes of farmyard manure per hectare or some other organic matter is applied 5 or 6 weeks before sowing. The fertilizer requirement of the irrigated wheat crop are as follows:\nWith assured fertilizer supply:\nNitrogen (N) @8- - 120 kg/ha\nPhosphorus (P2O5) @ 40- 60 kg/ha\nPotash (K2O) @ 40 kg/ha.\nUnder fertilizer constraints:\nN @ 60-80 kg/ha\nP2O5 @ 30-40 kg/ha\nK2O @ 20-25 kg/ha.</string>
    <string name="wheat5h">Application of Mannures and Fertilizer:</string>
    <string name="wheat6">The high yielding wheat varieties should be given five to six irrigations at their critical growth stages viz. Crown root initiation, tillering, jointing, flowering, milk and dough which come at 21-25 days after sowing (DAS), 45-60 DAS, 60-70 DAS, 90-95 DAS, 100-105 DAS and 120-125 DAS respectively. Off these irrigation at CRI stage is most important.</string>
    <string name="wheat6h">Irrigation:</string>
    <string name="wheat7">a) Harvesting:\nThe rain-fed crop reaches the harvest stage much earlier than the irrigated crop. The crop is harvested when the grains become hard and the straw becomes dry and brittle.The harvesting is mostly done by sickle. The crop is threshed by treading with cattle on the threshing-flour or by power driven thresher.\nb) Yield:\nThe national average yield of wheat grain is about 12 to 13.8 quintals per hectare.\nc) Storage:\nThe grains should be thoroughly dried before storage. The storage life of the grain is closely related to its moisture content. Grains with less than 10 percent moisture store well. The storage pits, bins or godowns should be moisture-proof and should be fumigated to keep down the stored – grain pests including rats. Zinc phosphide is very effective against rats.</string>
    <string name="wheat7h">Harvesting and Storage:</string>

    <string name="cotton1">Cotton (Gossypium sp.) is one of the most important commercial crops playing a key role in economics. In India cotton is cultivated in 9 million hectares in varied agro-climatic conditions across nine major States. Cotton cultivation offers 200 mandays/ha of employment. It employs directly and indirectly more than 60 million persons in its production, processing and marketing. India has the largest area under cotton, but its production is just 15.8 million bales, much lower for the vast area.</string>
    <string name="cotton2">Cotton is sown on ridges and furrows. For irrigated cotton the land is given a deep ploughing followed by two harrowings. Ridges and furrows having different spacing for irrigated and rainfed cotton. For irrigated cotton shallow ridges on 90cm spacing should be prepared which helps in irrigation. According to slope of land, length of ridges should be 6-9m.</string>
    <string name="cotton2h">Land preparation:</string>
    <string name="cotton3">Before sowing soil should be irrigated and after wapsa condition sowing should be done. Small shallow holes should be prepared on middle of the ridge upto 2-3 inch deep and applied recommended fertilizers and 1.0-1.5 gram of thimet and cover it with the soil. On each hill 3-4 cotton seeds should be dibble and cover completely with the soil and apply irrigation immediately. In North and Central India irrigated crop is sown from March-May and rainfed crop in June-July with the commencement of the monsoon. In South India the major portion of the irrigated and rainfed crop is planted in September-October, whereas the sowing of the rainfed crops extended upto November. In Karnataka desi cotton is usually sown in August-September.</string>
    <string name="cotton3h">Sowing:</string>
    <string name="cotton4">The fertilizer required for irrigated cotton is 100:50:50kg nitrogen, phosphorus and potash per hectare is recommended. The application of nitrogen is given by ring method. 20% nitrogen and whole phosphorus and potash should be given at the time of sowing and 40% nitrogen at the time of square formation and final 40% nitrogen at the time of flowering. In case of rainfed cotton fertilizer dose for desi variety is 50:50:25kg nitrogen, phosphorus and potash per hectare. For hybrid varieties fertilizer dose is 80:40:40 nitrogen, phosphorus and potash per hectare. 1/4 nitrogen and whole phosphorus and potash is given at the time of sowing while 1/2 nitrogen is given 4 weeks after sowing and remaining 1/4 nitrogen is given through spraying.</string>
    <string name="cotton4h">Fertilizer:</string>
    <string name="cotton5">In case of cotton germination, square initiation, flowering and boll formation and boll development are the critical stages for irrigation. The irrigated cotton crop is mostly sown after a preliminary irrigation and second the light watering is given in three or four days after germination. Subsequent watering depend upon the nature of the soil and the weather conditions. Flowering and boll formation are the critical stages from the point of view of irrigation. The summer sown crop gets frequent irrigations at intervals of 8-12 days. From sowing to square initiation period over irrigation should be avoided to stop the excessive vegetative growth. Skip row method should be followed if there is less availability of water. For first interval of irrigation water should be applied in first, third, fifth row and second interval water should be applied in second, forth and sixth row.</string>
    <string name="cotton5h">Irrigation:</string>
    <string name="cotton6">Cotton is sensitive for weed growth as weeds compete for water light and nutrients. If there is no control measures of weeds upto 70 days from cotton sowing there is chances of reduction in cotton production due to unsatisfactory growth of cotton crop. Therefore it is essential to keep the field weed free upto 2 months from sowing. To control the weeds 1-2 hand weeding and 2 harrowings should be done.</string>
    <string name="cotton6h">Weeding:</string>
    <string name="cotton7">Cotton is harvested by picking the fully opened bolls. First picking of cotton should be done when 30-35% bolls open fully. Picking should be done early in the morning. At the time of picking first pick clean cotton and then affected cotton. It should be picked separately of different varieties. Second picking should be done 15-20 days after first picking. After picking it should be dried 3-4 days in sun with due care. Cotton should be stored at clean and dry place.\nIrrigated cotton:\nImproved varieties- 20-24 quintal per hectare\nHybrid varieties-25-30 quintal per hectare\nRainfed cotton:\nDesi varieties 8-10 quintal per hectare,\nAmerican variety 11-12 quintal per hectare and\nHybrid varieties 12-15 quintal per hectare.</string>
    <string name="cotton7h">Harvesting and yield:</string>

    <string name="groundnut1">Groundnut (Arachis hypogaea L.) is important oilseed crop and oil content of the seed varies from 44-50%, depending on the varieties and agronomic conditions. It is also used in soap making, and in manufacturing cosmetics and lubricants, olein, stearin and their salts. Kernels are also eaten raw, roasted or sweetened. They are rich in protein and vitamins A, B and members of the B2 group. The cake can be used for manufacturing artificial fibre. The haulms are fed (green, dried or silaged) to livestock. Groundnut shell is used as fuel for manufacturing coarse boards, cork substitutes etc. Groundnut is also of value as a rotation crop. The production are concentrated in the four states of Gujarat, Andhra Pradesh, Tamil Nadu and Karnataka. Andhra Pradesh, Tamil Nadu, Karnataka and Orissa have irrigated areas.</string>
    <string name="groundnut2">For a kharif crop, with the onset of rains in May-June, the field is given two ploughing and the soil is pulverized well to obtain a good tilth. Harrows or tiller can be used for cultivation. If a field is infested with white grubs, chemicals, such as Heptachlor or Chlordane, are drilled at the rate of 25kg per ha. before final harrowing. For the irrigated crop, beds of convenient size may be made, depending upon the topography of the land, the nature of the irrigation source and the mode of lifting water.</string>
    <string name="groundnut2h">Cultivation:</string>
    <string name="groundnut3">Groundnut is raised mostly as a rainfed kharif crop, being sown from May to June, depending on the monsoon rains. It is sown as late as August or early September. As an irrigated crop it is grown to limited extent between January and March and between in May and July. Well-filled kernels should be selected and treated with 5g of Thiram or 3g of Captan per kg of kernels. The quantity of well-developed seeds required per hectare about 110 kg for semi spreading and spreading varieties and 120kg for the bunch varieties. The kharif crop is sown with a seed drill or with a suitable planter at a depth of 8-10 cm. for semi spreading and spreading varieties, the spacing between at he adjacent rows varies for m30-60cm and within the row from 10-15cm. For the rainfed bunch groundnut the inter-row spacing vary between 20 and 30cm and the intra-row spacing between 10 and 20cm.</string>
    <string name="groundnut3h">Sowing:</string>
    <string name="groundnut4">The kharif crop is caught in a long spell of drought, especially at the pod-formation stage, supplemental irrigation is given. For the irrigated groundnut, the frequency of irrigation depends on the soil texture, and the interval between irrigation ranges from 8-12 days. The peg-formation stage is critical.</string>
    <string name="groundnut4h">Irrigation:</string>
    <string name="groundnut5">Pest Leaf-miner\nCaterpillars mine the tender leaves and later fold the adjacent leaves to feed within. Pest active during July to December; drought, with occasional showers favourable.\nControl\nDust 4% Carbaryl,\nGroundnut aphid\nVector of a virus disease (rosette), dry and warm weather, favourable.\nControl\nSpray 0.03% Dimethoate or Phosphamidon, Monocroptophos or Methyl-demeton\nWhite grub\nThe adults emerge immediately after the monsoon; grubs feed on roots and kill the plants.\nControl\nGrubs very difficult to kill; the application of 10% Phorate granules is to be effective.</string>
    <string name="groundnut5h">Plant protection:</string>
    <string name="groundnut6">Root rot\nReddish brown discolouration on the stem, spreading and the plant collapsing; tissues blackened and numerous tiny black scleriotia are formed\nControl\nPractise crop rotation, treat seed with Agrosan GN or Ceresan or Thiram @ 3gram per kg of seed.\nTikka disease or leaf spot\nDark spots surrounded by a bright-yellow ring on the leaves and sometimes on the petiole and the stem; premature leaf-shedding is characteristic.\nControl\nSpray with Brestan or with 4:4:50 Bordeaux mixture or with 0.2% Ziram or Zineb or Maneb.\nBunchy top\nLeaves reduced in size and malformed; suppression of the internodes; partial sterility.\nControl\nUse well-developed disease free seeds, rogue out diseased plants.</string>
    <string name="groundnut6h">Disease:</string>
    <string name="groundnut8">Fertilizer recommended for rainfed crop is 6.25 tonnes farmyard manure and 10-25kg nitrogen (N), 20-40kg phosphorus (P2O5) and 20-40kg potash (K2O) per hectare. For irrigated crop 12.5 tonnes farmyard manure and 20-40kg nitrogen (N), 40-90kg phosphorus (P2O5) and 20-40kg potash (K2O) per hectare. The application of nitrogen (N) in two equal splits doses, one before sowing and the other 30 days after sowing. The application of a culture of Rhizobium as seed treatment is beneficial in increasing nodulation and nitrogen fixation. The application of gypsum at 500kg per ha at the pegging stage will enhance pod formation.</string>
    <string name="groundnut8h">Fertilizer:</string>
    <string name="groundnut7">The prominent symptoms of maturity are the yellowing of leaves, the shedding of the older leaves, the development of the proper colour of the testa and a dark tint inside the shell. The bunch and semi-spreading varieties are usually harvested by hand pulling when there is adequate moisture in the soil. The spreading types, on the other hand, are harvested by digging or by ploughing or working a blade harrow. The pulled out plants are stacked for a few days for drying and are stripped afterwards.</string>
    <string name="groundnut7h">Harvesting and yield:</string>

    <string name="jowar1">Sorghum (Sorghum vulgare Pers.), popularly known as jowar, is the most important food and fodder crop of dryland agriculture. The annual area under it ranges between 17 and 18 million hectares and the annual production between 8 and 10 million tonnes.Sorghum is originated in India and Africa. It is also said that its origin is Abyssinia and from there it was brought to USA and European countries.Jowar is mainly concentrated in the peninsular and central India. Maharashtra, Karnataka, Andhra Pradesh, Madhya Pradesh, Gujarat, Rajasthan, Uttar Pradesh (the Bundelkhand region) and Tamil Nadu are the major jowar – growing states. Other states grow sorghum in small areas primarily for fodder.</string>
    <string name="jowar2">Deep summer ploughing with mould board plough soon after rabi crop is harvested and leaving the soil exposed to sun until onset of monsoon is a common practice. With the onset of monsoon the land should be ploughed twice by country plough. But the soil for grain crop should be pulverised for a fine tilth by harrowing and cross plankings. If desired, field should be levelled before sowing so that rainwater may be well distributed throughout the field.</string>
    <string name="jowar2h">Land Preparation:</string>
    <string name="jowar3">a) Sowing time:Sorghum crop is grown in almost all the seasons of the year. In Northern India conditions it is grown in kharif season but in Southern India the crop is grown during Rabi and summer seasons. Kharif crop should be sown soon after first break of monsoon rains i.e. nearly in last week of June. Therefore, the best sowing time is in last week of June to first week of July depending upon onset of monsoon. Whereas rabi jawar is sown in the month of October to November.\nb) Spacing:A spacing of 40-45 cm between the rows and 15-20 cm between the plants is quite satisfactory.\nc) Seed rate: Required plant population may be obtained by using a seed rate of 8-12 kg/ha. The seeds are sown about 3-4 cm deep in the furrows.</string>
    <string name="jowar3h">Sowing:</string>
    <string name="jowar4">Sorghum is an exhaustive crop and it depletes soil fertility very fast, if proper care is not taken. The fertilizer doses differ from type to type and nature of crop to be grown e.g. local varieties need less quantity than hybrid ones. Similarly, irrigated crop requires higher doses than rainfed ones no matter whether it is a local or high yielding variety. Considering all these points an optimum dose may be found out from the following details: an optimum dose of nitrogen for rainfed high yielding and local varieties of irrigated crop should be 60-80kg/ha while for irrigated high yielding varieties it should be between 120-150 kg/ha. In case of heavy soils one single application gives better results than split application but in case of light soils split application i.e. half basal and remaining half as top-dressing at knee-height stage or 30-35 days after sowing is preferred. Under low rainfall or in rainfed areas top-dressing of nitrogen is not required. On an average a dose of 40-60 kg P2O5/ha is found to be good. Placement at 4-6 cm depth has given better results. However, under normal conditions it is mostly basal placed. Potash at the rate of 40kg/ha applied at the time of field preparation gives good result.</string>
    <string name="jowar4h">Application of mannurs and fertilizers:</string>
    <string name="jowar5">Sorghum is a fairly drought resistant crop and it does very well in areas receiving 50 cm well distributed rainfall but it cannot withstand waterlogging at any stage of crop growth. The most critical growth stages for irrigation are knee-height stage, flowering and grain filling stages at which the crop should be ensured for proper moisture conditions so that the crop does not suffer from moisture stress.Contrary to this in kharif crop an efficient drainage must be provided as the crop cannot tolerate water accumulation for more than few hours, therefore, in low lying areas sowing of crop on 5-7cm high ridges or sowing in flat beds followed by light earthing is a remedy for stagnant water in the field.</string>
    <string name="jowar5h">Irrigation:</string>
    <string name="jowar6">Sorghum is found to be attacked by shoot-fly, stem-borer and midges mainly and they cause a considerable reduction in grain and stover yields.Manual weedings and hoeings help in solving the weed problem but it is possible only during rabi and arid cropping seasons while rains do not permit the manual weeding or hoeing during kharif season. Application of herbicides like atrazine @ 0.5 kg a.i./ha or Propazine @1.0 kg a.i./ha dissolved in 900-1000 liters of water, therefore, becomes obviously essential to control weeds. These herbicides should be applied before emergence of sorghum seedlings.</string>
    <string name="jowar6h">Plant protection Measures:</string>
    <string name="jowar7">a) Harvesting:\nThe high yielding varieties mature in about 100-120 days duration after which they are harvested. Generally two methods of harvesting i.e. either stalk-cut or cutting of earheads by sickles are employed. However, in foreign countries sorghum harvesters are used. In case of stock cut method the plants are cut from near the ground level, the stalks are tied into bundles of convenient removed from plants, while in later case the earheads, after their removal from the standing crop, are piled up on the threshing floor and after few days they are threshed. Threshing of earheds is done either by beating them with sticks or by trampling them under bullock’s feet. Later method is quicker and is practiced by majority of farmers who use to grow the crop on larger scale.\nb) Yield:\nThe grain yield of improved varieties under assured water supply ranges between 25-35 quintals/ha and that of hay or karvi between 150-170 quintals/ha.\nc) Storage:\nthe harvested grains are sun-dried and storage is conventional.</string>
    <string name="jowar7h">Harvesting and threshing:</string>

    <string name="potato1">The Potato, a native of South America occupies a largest area any single vegetable in the world. It has a special value as food. The consumption of potato per head is very low in India as compared to that of Western Countries. Potato belongs to family Solanaceae and botanical name is Solanum tuberosum.</string>
    <string name="potato2">Potato can be grown well in fertile and well-drained soil. Potato grows well in soil having pH 4.8-5.4. Heavy soil should be avoided. The short day conditions are highly favourable for economic yield of potato crops. To secure good for potato a day length of 12-13 hours is needed and night temperature 200 C increase tuberization.</string>
    <string name="potato3">The potato belongs to family Solanaceae. It is a harbaceos annual and propagated by tubers, the thick underground stems which are called stolons. The stolon are slender, arising from buds, length and diameter varies with varieties. Eyes on the potato are buds and one or more develops into stem and leaves. Stem may be green, purple or light violet. Leaves are compound with opposite leaflets. Stems and leaves prostrate or erect. Height of plant one to two feet depending on variety. Roots are shallow and superficial, extend upto two feet. Flowers are about an inch in diameter, corolla white to purple or violet. Fruit is a berry but commonly not developed, spherical, half to one inch in diameter, purple or black. Seeds are about the size of mustard, hetrozygous, not use for propagation except for breeding purpose. The size, shape, colour of skin of tubers varies with variety. The flush colour may be white, light yellow, pink or light blue.</string>
    <string name="potato3h">Planting Habits:</string>
    <string name="potato4">F.Y.M.  250-400 g/hectare\n120-160 kg/hectare N\n80-120 kg/hectare P\n80-120 kg/hectare K\nTo be incorporated into the soil 3 to 4 weeks before planting half dose of nitrogen full dose of P2O5 and K2O as basal dressing at planting and remaining nitrogen dose is given at the time of earthing up.</string>
    <string name="potato4h">Application of Manures and Fertilizer:</string>
    <string name="potato5">Potato needs irrigation at frequent intervals, depending upon the soil and climatic conditions. Usually 6 irrigation is sufficient. Pre-sowing irrigation followed by 5-6 light irrigations.</string>
    <string name="potato5h">Irrigation:</string>
    <string name="potato6">Cut worms – Spray Dursban 20 EC or apply Phorate in soil.\nCaterpillar – Spray Thiodan or BHC (10%)\nAphid -- Spray Rogor or Nuvacron or Malathion\nJassids -- Spray Metasystox (0.1%)\nDiseases:Nematodes -- Fumigate soil with D-D\nEarly Blight – Spray Dithane M-45 (0.2%)\nLate blight -- Spray Dithane M-45 or Dithane Z-78 or Difolatan or Zineb.\nScab --Disinfect tubers with Agallol-6 or Mercuric fungicides.\nVirus disease – Use certified seeds. Spray Metasystox (0.1%) or apply Timet or Furadon in furrow before planting.</string>
    <string name="potato6h">Plant Protection Pests:</string>
    <string name="potato7">Potato is harvested from the time it is sufficient size until the vines are fully ripe. The average yield varies from 20 to 30 tonnes per hectare. The best method storing potato is in cold stores at 2.20 C to 3.30 C and at 75 to 80% relative humidity.</string>
    <string name="potato7h">Yield:</string>

    <string name="green1">Green gram (Phaseolus aureus Roxb) is important pulse crops. The grains (whole or split) are used as a pulse or made into flour, and into straw and husk as fodder for cattle. Grains are also eaten whole (after germinating them), parched, salted, with sugar or boiled with condiments. The important states producing this pulse are Madhya Pradesh, Maharashtra, Uttar Pradesh, Punjab and Andhra Pradesh, Rajasthan, Karnataka and Tamil Nadu.</string>
    <string name="green2">For the pure crop in the kharif season, the land is ploughed once or twice and harrowed to obtain a rough tilth. The summer crop can be sown dry in furrows in between the rows of the previous crop, followed by irrigation.This pulse does best on deep, well-drained loams in the alluvial tract in the north as well as on the red and black soils of peninsular and southern India. It is also cultivated on light or shallow stony soils to clayey soils.</string>
    <string name="green2h">Cultivation:</string>
    <string name="green3">The kharif crop is sown in June to July, and the rabi crop in September or October. The spring crop is to be sown by 15 February and harvested by the middle of May. The summer crop is sown by 15 April. The seed may be sown by broadcasting or it may be drilled in furrows behind a plough, or with a three-or four-coultered desi drill, in rows 20-30cm apart. The seed-rate varies from 15-20kg per hectare when sown alone and for mixed crop 2-6kg per hectare.</string>
    <string name="green3h">Sowing:</string>
    <string name="green4">Manuring with 25-40kg per ha of phosphorus (P2O5) and 25kg per ha of nitrogen (N) should be given at the time sowing. Also seed treatment with biofertilizer viz. Rhizobium at the rate of 25gram per kg of seed is beneficial.</string>
    <string name="green4h">Fertilizer:</string>
    <string name="green5">Being kharif crop green gram is not required irrigation unless there is dry spell during the kharif season. In summer irrigation should be given according to soil type. Irrigation interval should be 8-10 days in summer. Flowering and pod filling are the critical stages for irrigation.</string>
    <string name="green5h">Irrigation:</string>
    <string name="green6">1. Aphids\nThe nymphs and adults suck the sap. The affected leaves turns yellow, get wrinkled and distorted. The insect also exude honeydew on which fungus develops, rapidly covers the plant with sooty mould that interferes with the photosynthetic activity of the plant.\nControl:\nSpraying with 0.05% Endosulfan, 0.02% Phosphamidon, 0.03% Dimethoate, Methyl demeton or Thiometon control the pest effectively.\n2. Thrips\nThe adults and nymphs feed on leaves. They scrape the epidermis and such the oozing sap. As a result, light brown patches appear on infested leaves. The affected leaves curl and become dry.\nControlSpraying with 0.05% Endosulfan, 0.02% Phosphamidon, 0.03% Dimethoate, Methyl demeton or Thiometon control the pest effectively.\n3. Pod borer\nCaterpillars feed on tender foliage and young pods. They make holes in the pods and feed on developing seeds by inserting anterior half portion of their body inside the pods.\nControl\nIn early stage of attack handpicking of the caterpillars and their destruction. Ploughing fields after the harvest of crop would expose the pupae, which would be destroyed by birds. Spraying the crop with 0.05% Quinalphos or Fenitrohion can successfully control the pest. Spray with HaNPV @ 250 LE/ha.</string>
    <string name="green6h">Plant protection Pests:\n</string>
    <string name="green7">1. Leaf spot\nAngular brown or red spots, with grey or brown centre and reddish-purple border on leave, stalk and pods\nControl\nSpray with Bordeaux mixture (5:5:50) or 0.2% Ziram.\n2. Powdery mildew\nWhite powdery patches on leaves and other green parts, later becoming dull coloured and are studded with black dot.\nControl:\nDust the crop with finely powdered sulphur (200-mesh) @ 20kg/ha.</string>
    <string name="green7h">Diseases:</string>
    <string name="green8">To avoid loss because of the shattering of pods, the crop is harvested before it is dead ripe. One or two rounds of the picking of pods are also recommended to avoid losses because of the shattering. The plants are uprooted or cut with a sickle, are dried on the threshing-floor for a week or ten days and threshed by beating with sticks, and are winnowed with baskets. The average yield of grain from a pure crop varieties from 5-6q per ha, whereas yields up to 10-15q per ha.</string>
    <string name="green8h">Harvesting and yield:</string>

    <string name="ok">ok</string>
    <string name="wheat0">Wheat</string>
    <string name="cotton0">COTTON</string>
    <string name="sugarcane0">SUGARCANE</string>
    <string name="red_soil_in_india_is_sandier_and_less_clayey_in_nature_and_do_not_acquire_any_important_nutrient_as_they_are_poor_in_nitrogen_lime_and_phosphorous_properties_the_lowermost_area_of_red_soil_is_dark_in_color_and_very_fertile_while_the_upper_layer_is_sandy_and_porous_thus_proper_use_of_fertilizers_and_irrigation_yields_high_production_of_various_crops_types_of_crops_like_cotton_wheat_rice_pulses_millets_tobacco_oil_seeds_potatoes_are_grown"><![CDATA[Red Soil in India is sandier and less clayey in nature and do not acquire any important nutrient as they are poor in nitrogen, lime and phosphorous. \nProperties: The lowermost area of red soil is dark in color and very fertile, while the upper layer is sandy and porous. Thus, proper use of fertilizers and irrigation yields high production of various crops.]]></string>
    <string name="black_soil_is_also_called_as_regur_soil_or_black_cotton_soil_it_is_the_third_major_group_of_soil_in_india_and_forms_the_top_part_of_the_earth_s_surface_that_includes_disintegrated_rock_humus_inorganic_and_organic_materials_the_soil_is_in_black_colour_and_is_formed_by_the_weathering_of_igneous_rock_properties_black_soil_is_a_black_colored_soil_rich_in_humus_and_contains_a_high_percentage_of_phosphoric_acid_phosphorus_and_ammonia_it_is_also_rich_in_iron_lime_calcium_potash_aluminium_and_magnesium_these_soils_are_very_fertile_and_are_useful_in_the_cultivation_of_various_types_of_crops_types_of_crops_like_cotton_tobacco_chilly_oil_seeds_jowar_ragi_and_maize_grow_well_in_it"><![CDATA[Black soil is also called as regur soil or black cotton soil. It is the third major group of soil in India and forms the top part of the earth\'s surface. The soil is in black colour and is formed by the weathering of igneous rock. \nProperties: Black soil is a black-colored soil rich in humus and contains a high percentage of phosphoric acid, phosphorus, and ammonia. These soils are very fertile and are useful in the cultivation of various types of crops.]]></string>
    <string name="clay_soil_is_a_type_of_soil_that_consists_of_a_large_number_of_clay_particles_and_a_very_small_amount_of_humus_and_silt_this_soil_is_so_compact_that_it_cannot_trap_air_clay_is_a_type_of_fine_grained_natural_soil_material_containing_clay_minerals_1_hydrous_aluminium_phyllosilicates_e_g_kaolin_al2si2o5_oh_4_properties_the_small_size_of_the_particles_and_their_unique_crystal_structures_give_clay_materials_special_properties_these_properties_include_cation_exchange_capabilities_plastic_behaviour_when_wet_catalytic_abilities_swelling_behaviour_and_low_permeability">Clay soil is a type of soil that consists of a large number of clay particles and a very small amount of humus and silt. This soil is so compact that it cannot trap air. Clay is a type of fine-grained natural soil material containing clay minerals. \nProperties: They have unique crystal structures give clay materials special properties. These properties include cation exchange capabilities, plastic behaviour when wet, catalytic abilities, swelling behaviour, and low permeability.</string>
    <string name="soils">Soils</string>
    <string name="soil_is_the_loose_surface_material_that_covers_most_land_it_consists_of_inorganic_particles_and_organic_matter_soil_provides_the_structural_support_to_plants_used_in_agriculture_and_is_also_their_source_of_water_and_nutrients_the_mixture_of_rock_particles_and_humus_is_called_the_soil_living_organisms_such_as_bacteria_plant_roots_and_earthworm_are_also_important_parts_of_any_soil_the_soil_is_classified_on_the_basis_of_the_proportion_of_particles_of_various_sizes"><![CDATA[Soil is the loose surface material that covers most land. It consists of inorganic particles and organic matter. Soil provides the structural support to plants used in agriculture and is also their source of water and nutrients.The mixture of rock particles and humus is called the soil. Living organisms, such as bacteria, plant roots and earthworm are also important parts of any soil. The soil is classified on the basis of the proportion of particles of various sizes.]]></string>
    <string name="types_of_soils">Types Of Soils</string>
    <string name="logout">Logout</string>
    <string name="soils1">SOILS</string>
    <string name="welcome1">WELCOME</string>
    <string name="crops_suitable_for_soil">Crops Suitable For Soil</string>
    <string name="step_by_step_guidance_for_crop_cultivation">Step By Step Guidance For Crop Cultivation</string>

    <string name="nursery_bed_preparation">Nursery Bed Preparation:</string>
    <string name="raising_of_seedlings">Raising Of Seedlings:</string>
    <string name="land_preparation_and_spacing">Land Preparation and Spacing:</string>
    <string name="manures_and_fertilizers">Manures and Fertilizers:</string>
    <string name="harvesting_and_yield">Harvesting and Yield:</string>



    <string name="potatoyt">Youtube video <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rs6cV4BhGVM">youtube.com</a></string>
    <string name="potatoweb">Website <a href="https://www.apnikheti.com/en/pn/agriculture/horticulture/vegetable-crops/potato">website.com</a></string>

    <string name="playlist">Tips for crop cultivation (Youtube Playlist) <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLc0Ir_68GVyCIKQPckjTaF3CJGzTXyJSc">youtube.com</a></string>
    
    <string name="greengramweb">Website <a href="https://agritech.tnau.ac.in/agriculture/CropProduction/Pulses/pulses_greengram.html">website.com</a></string>
    <string name="greengramyt">Youtube video <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7KXCJQOVImA">youtube.com</a></string>

    <string name="sugaryt">Youtube video <a href="https://youtu.be/jv-lKPZd_30">youtube.com</a></string>
    <string name="sugarweb">Website <a href="http://www.agritech.tnau.ac.in/expert_system/sugar/cultivationpractices.html">website.com</a></string>
    
    <string name="paddyyt">Youtube videos</string>
    <string name="paddyyt1">1.<a href="https://youtu.be/Zid9-aFBSlU">LandPreparation</a></string>
    <string name="paddyyt2">2.<a href="https://youtu.be/R2rqGqLCDNg">SowingSeeds</a></string>
    <string name="paddyyt3">3.<a href="https://youtu.be/P2DV2ewXyS8">Harvesting</a></string>
    <string name="paddyyt4">4.<a href="https://youtu.be/BqMv-p2QntM">Threshing1</a></string>
    <string name="paddyyt5">5.<a href="https://youtu.be/A1WCid_Zx8Y">Threshing2</a></string>
    <string name="paddyweb">Website <a href="https://www.farmingindia.in/paddy-cultivation/">website.com</a></string>

    <string name="cabbageyt">Youtube video <a href="https://youtu.be/V3EEc3OHOjk">youtube.com</a></string>
    <string name="cabbageweb">Website <a href="https://www.apnikheti.com/en/pn/agriculture/horticulture/vegetable-crops/cabbage">website.com</a></string>

    <string name="cottonyt">Youtube video <a href="https://youtu.be/KsZ9bX4KQKw">youtube.com</a></string>
    <string name="cottonweb">Website <a href="https://agritech.tnau.ac.in/agriculture/agri_cropproduction_fibre_irrigatedcotton.html">website.com</a></string>

    <string name="groundnutyt">Youtube video <a href="https://youtu.be/ydDabCoFhlY">youtube.com</a></string>
    <string name="groundnutweb">Website <a href="https://www.apnikheti.com/en/pn/agriculture/crops/oilseeds/groundnut">website.com</a></string>

    <string name="wheatyt">Youtube video <a href="https://youtu.be/qrUi9ez5g3M">youtube.com</a></string>
    <string name="wheatweb">Website <a href="https://www.apnikheti.com/en/pn/agriculture/crops/cereals/wheat-kanak-gehu">website.com</a></string>

    <string name="jowaryt">Youtube video <a href="https://youtu.be/U4odgvVCblc">youtube.com</a></string>
    <string name="jowarweb">Website <a href="https://www.agrifarming.in/jowar-farming">website.com</a></string>

    <string name="reference">Reference</string>

</resources>